# 大家好 今天又下雨啦 天天下雨
Hi everyone! It rains again today. It rains everyday.
# 我秤一下那個狗 看一下多重啦
Let me weigh the dogs, and see how heavy they are.
# 我先秤一下我
I weigh myself first.
# 秤不對的 怎麼那麼重
Something's wrong? Why am I so heavy?
# 胖啦
I've put on weight.
# 你看 現在109啦
Look! I'm now 109.
(Note: The unit is "jin, where 1 "jin" = 500 grams)
# (沒字幕)
# 公斤秤
The reading is in kilograms.
(Note: The unit is "jin, where 1 "jin" = 500 grams)
# 我來秤一下這個 這個 這個鬆獅一樣的
Let me weigh this one, which, which looks like a Chow Chow.
# 大胖狗過來 稱一下你多重啦
Big chubby dog. Let me see how heavy you are.
# 哎呀 那麼重它
Aya! He's so heavy!
# 70 71
70, 71
# 71公斤
71 kilograms.
# 108 71
108, 71...
# 計算機多快呀 108減71
How convenient a calculator is. 108 minus 71
# 不是哦
Ah, no!
# 錯啦
I got it wrong.
# 71乘以2等於142減108
71 times 2 is 142, minus 108...
# 誒 34斤
Eh? 34 "jin"
# 看一下小黑
Let's see Blacky.
# 小黑 小黑 小黑我秤一下你啊
Blacky, Blacky, I'm gonna weigh you.
# 來
C'mon!
# 哎呀 好重
Aya! Heavy!
# 76 76斤
76, 76 "jin"
# 76斤 (註︰這裡他說錯了，是76公斤，不過我不為他澄清了)
76 "jin"
# 哎喲
Ayo!
# 76乘以2
76 times 2
# 152減去108
152 minus 108
# 44斤
44 "jin"
# 你看
Look!
# 它那麼小就那麼重
He's so small, but is already that heavy.
# 小黑它都懷孕啦
Blacky is now pregnant.
# 這大母狗也壞孕啦
This big mom is also pregnant.
# 這大母狗就不秤它啦 肚子那麼大
I'm not gonna weigh the big mom. Her belly is so big now.
# 嘿 秤一下你的
Hey! Let me weigh you.
# 嘿喲
Heyo!
# 最不聽話的那條
He's the naughtiest!
# 跑啦
Gone!
# 秤一下這條
Let me weigh this one.
# 跑那麼快
She runs so fast!
# 秤一下你 你看 今天 今天跑去淋雨啦
Let me wiegh you. Look! Today, today she went into the rain.
# 1斤7兩
1.7
# 公斤3斤4兩
in kilograms, so 3.4 "jin"
# 可以喲 跟竹鼠那麼大
No bad. She's as big as a bamboo rat.
# 你看 本來很白的這個
Look! She should be very white, this puppy.
# 你看 跑出外面去淋一下雨 又粘了一點泥土回來
Look! She ran outside and went into the rain. Then some mud has stuck on her.
# 就這樣子啦
And she's so dirty now.
# 你看 給你
Look! Take her,
# 一起玩
and have fun with her.
# 還有一條呢
Where's the last one?
# 把它摞出來
I'm gonna draw her out.
# 這條 這條應該最瘦 最小
This one, this one should be the skinniest, and the smallest.
# 又瘦又小
Skinny and small
# 1斤7兩哦 跟那個一樣的
1.7, the same as that one.
# 看上去那麼大
She looks so big.
# 體重都是一樣的
But there's no difference in the weights,
# 跟它一樣小
as small as her.
# 我怎麼那麼重
How did I become so heavy?
# 一百 零八
A hundred, and, eight
# 斤2兩
point two "jin"
# 還有一條大公狗不知道跑哪裡去啦
There's one big boy. But he's gone to who-knows-somewhere.
# 它那條是最壯的
He's the most bulky one.
# 抓不到它
I can't catch him.
# 下次來秤
I'll weigh him next time.
# 兄弟家還養了幾隻兔子 我們去看一下
My buddy is keeping some bunnies at his place. Let's go and have a look.
# 他家兔子很靚的
His bunnies are really beautiful.
# 這個是兄弟家的秤
This is my buddy's balace.
# 給它還回去
Let me return it to him.
# 算啦 不還啦 放到這裡來
Forget it. I'm not returning it. Let me keep it here.
# 下次來還
I'll return it next time.
# 你看 這個小兔子
Look! This little bunny
# 吃飽了哈 肚子那麼大
It has eaten a lot. Its belly is so big.
# 哎喲
Ayo!
# 這裡 這裡也有 這裡一個誒
Here, here too, here's one, eh!
# 這個黑的
This one is black,
# 黑的小兔子 看到沒
a black bunny, see?
# 好可愛啊 肚子好大
It's lovely! The belly is so big.
# 還小
It's still small.
# 這個灰的 這個灰的最可愛
This grey one, this grey one is the loveliest.
# 這個灰兔子看到沒 哦
It's a grey bunny, see? Oh!
# 中間還有
There's a bunch of hair,
# 一坨毛
in the middle,
# 白的
and is white.
# 哎喲 爪人的
Ayo! It scratched me!
# 哎喲
Ayo!
# 打扁你去
I beat you hard!
# 這個兔就像我們以前那個兔子
The bunny looks like the one that used to be with us.
# 好靚哦 這個兔子 你看
It's so beautiful, this bunny. Look!
# 有點像
It's a bit like,
# 有點像我以前那個兔子
looks a bit like the bunny that used to be with me.
# 它會吃稻草
They eat straw.
# 再加點這個 香蕉葉 香蕉葉給它們吃
Let me give them some, you know, banana leaves, some banana leaves as well.
# 它們很喜歡吃香蕉葉的哦
They love banana leaves, you know.
# 小兔子
Little bunnies!
# 去不去我家玩
You wanna go home with me?
# 要不要去面玩
You wanna have fun upstairs?
# 去不去
Do you?
# 好害羞啊 它們
They're very shy.
# 你看 這隻
Look! This one,
# 小兔子
this little bunny
# 好可愛呀 這些
They're really lovely.
# 它這個是寵物兔來的哦 長不大的
They're pet bunnies and they won't get big.
# 就那麼小一點
They're always that tiny.
# 天天給它葉葉子給它吃 你看 吃這個香蕉葉
They're given veggie leaves every day. Look! They're eating the banana leaves.
# 這邊都還藏了幾個哦 看到沒
A few more are hiding here, see?
# 躲到這裡來吃
They're having their meal, hiding here.
# 害羞 是不是
Shy, aren't you?
# 你看 這個就像
Look! This one is like,
# 這就像 那個甚麼
it's like, I mean, you know,
# 現偶一樣的
like a doll.
# 你看 這個兔子
Look! This bunny,
# 它都紅眼哦
its eyes have turned red.
# 它現在肚子餓啦 想吃菜葉子 這個香蕉葉來的
Now they're hungry and want some veggie leaves. These are banana leaves.
# 特意搞了點香蕉葉給它吃
I've fetched some banana leaves, exclusively for them.
# 一摸它它就不動啦 是啊
It's like a statue once a pet it, yea.
# 很乖的哦 這個
It's a good bunny, this one.
# 繼續吃
Go on eating!
# 呵呵 動都不敢動
Ho ho! It dares not move an inch.
# 不要怕啊
Fear not!
# 這灰兔子
This grey bunny,
# 這沒尾巴 它尾巴那麼一點點
it doesn't have a tail. Its tail is just a tiny little bit here.
# 我一動它 它就躺著那裡 享受是不是
Once I pet it, it lies here and is, enjoying, isn't it?
# 不敢動是不是
You dare not move, right?
# 這個兔子要蓋起來啊 不蓋起來它要
The bunnies need to be covered up. Otherwise, they're gonna,
# 它要跑
gonna run away.
# 它會跳走
They can jump out from the cell.
# 好啦 看一下那個溫泉
Look! Let's have a look at the hot spring.
# 現在下雨應該很乾淨 去那泡一下腳
It's raining now so it must be very clean there. Let me soak my feet.
# 這兩隻都是以前那個母狗生的
These two dogs are children of the big mom.
# 你看 現在都玩沙子它
Look! He's now playing with the sand.
# 來 給你小石頭給你 哈哈哈 好吃的
C'mon! I give you a small rock! Ha ha ha! It's tasty.
# 你看 這個溫泉 天氣熱都沒人泡 這裡
Look! This hot spring, it's hot and so nobody's here now.
# 泡一下腳
Let me soak my feet.
# 太熱啦
It's too hot.
# 哎喲
Ayo!
# 這個天氣隨便一泡下就上來
With this weather, a second or two is already enough.
# 好啦
Alright!
# 泡好啦
Enough!
# 泡一下就很燙啦
Just a second and it's already boiling.
# 這個時候不適合泡
It's not a good season for hot spring.
# 太熱啦
It's too hot.
# 冬天的時候就爽
It's really nice in winter.
# 冬天的時候泡在這裡
Soaking in the hot spring in winter,
# 多暖和哇
it's so warm!